traveloregon.com 2018-12-28

# Privacy Policy & Terms of Use - Travel Oregon

### About Travel Oregon

TravelOregon.com is the official website of The Oregon Tourism Commission (dba Travel Oregon), the official destination marketing agency for the State of Oregon.

Our postal address is:  
530 Center St NE, Suite 200

Salem, Oregon 97301

We can be reached via email at  _[info@traveloregon.com](mailto:info@traveloregon.com)_

### Privacy

Your privacy is important to Travel Oregon and we will treat any of your information with care.

Our Privacy Statement lets you know how we handle both personally identifiable information you share with us through our digital and printed communication vehicles and non-personally identifiable information that we may automatically collect.

### Personal Information Collection

You may use our web sites, digital newsletters and other forms of internet-based communications to learn about Travel Oregon products and services without disclosing any personal information beyond what you provided when requesting authorized publications, both digital or printed. We may ask you to provide us with personal information, for example, to access or use certain features or if you request additional information from our partners. Information that may be requested by Travel Oregon may include, but is not limited to: contact information, such as name, address, email address, and telephone number; demographic information, such as household information, age group, etc. and information about your travel interests.

### Personal Information Uses

It is Travel Oregon’s policy to treat any personally identifiable information submitted via our web site as strictly confidential. Travel Oregon does not make your personal information available to third parties for any reason, except to fulfill requests made by you and / or your company or as may be required by the Oregon Public Records Law. Guide requests from outside of the United States and Canada may be sent to third parties contracted with Travel Oregon for processing and fulfillment. Guide requests in the United States and Canada that include a specification for additional information are made available to approved Travel Oregon partners as a way to fulfill the request. This information is stored in a secure database that is accessible only by the approved Travel Oregon partners. Requesting the additional information is not required when requesting printed travel materials from Travel Oregon.

Travel Oregon may use the information you voluntarily offer to inform you directly about information, products or services that may be of interest to you, improve content on our web site or electronic newsletter, or to assist with marketing research. We may disclose your personal information as required by law, in conjunction with a public records request, government inquiry, or in litigation or dispute resolution.

### Cookies

We use tracking tools such as cookies, or other technologies or methods of integration that may be placed in the browser of your device (e.g., computer or mobile phone) to collect non-personally identifiable information such as internet protocol (IP) addresses to provide us with general location data, sometimes across multiple devices. We may share with our service providers your IP address to monitor how effective our advertisements are at inspiring you to visit Oregon. IP addresses may also be collected for marketing purposes when you take other actions like submitting a form on the website or clicking on an email link. When users with an IP address in the EU or an unknown location arrives on TravelOregon.com, they will see language on pages where we enable cookies. If you do not wish to accept the cookies, you may set your browser to reject the cookies (consult the instructions for your browser on how to do this), although doing so may affect your experience with certain functionalities on the website.

### Links to Outside Websites

This site may contain links to third party sites not controlled by Travel Oregon, which therefore are not covered by this privacy statement, such as those belonging to Travel Oregon partners and advertisers. We recommend that you check the privacy statement of other sites you visit before providing any personal information.

### Data Storage

We will keep your information for as long as we need it for the purpose for which it is being processed. For example, when you request a printed travel guide from us, we will keep the information related to your order so we can fulfill the specific request you have made. After that, we will keep the information for a period which enables us to handle or respond to any questions or concerns related to the order. The information may also be retained so that we can continue to improve your experience with us.

We will actively review the information we hold and delete it securely, or in some cases, anonymize it, when there is no longer a legal, business or customer need for it to be retained. If you stop interacting with us, we will remove or anonymize your information after 7 years.

### Access and Portability of Data:

You have the right to review your information at any time. If you would like to review your information within our contacts database, please contact [info@traveloregon.com](mailto:info@traveloregon.com). If a user requests access to this data, Travel Oregon will provide the user with a copy of the data in either .csv or .xls format within 30 days.

### Modification of Personal Data

You have the right to ask Travel Oregon to modify personal data if it is inaccurate or incomplete. To request changes to personal data, please contact [info@traveloregon.com](mailto:info@traveloregon.com)

### Data Deletion

You have the right to request that Travel Oregon permanently delete any personal data that we may have stored about you, including email tracking history, call records and form submissions. To request deletion of data, please contact [info@traveloregon.com](mailto:info@traveloregon.com).

### Data Processing

You have the right to request that Travel Oregon stop the processing of your personal information for marketing purposes including analytics for the purposes of targeted marketing, including online advertising. An example would be if your guide order specified an interest in family-friendly travel, we will use analytics to show you family-friendly travel content on traveloregon.com. Contact [info@traveloregon.com](mailto:info@traveloregon.com) if you would like to request that we stop processing your data for marketing purposes.

### Unsubscribe/Opt-Out

We do not want to send you information you do not want to receive. All of our email newsletters include links in the footer of the email for managing all aspects of your subscription, including the ability to globally unsubscribe from such communications. You may also contact [info@traveloregon.com](mailto:info@traveloregon.com) to request to be opted out of our email communications. If you wish to opt out of cookies that allow us to serve our advertisements while you are in Oregon, and collect aggregate information on arrivals,  _[click here](http://dc.arrivalist.com/optout/)_.

### Changes to Privacy

Travel Oregon retains the right to change this Privacy Policy Statement. For your benefit, we will post changes to this page in a timely manner.

### Content

Content and information contained in this site has been compiled by the Oregon Tourism Commission, based on data submitted directly from local tourism promotion partners and business entities. While every effort is made to ensure the accuracy of this information, all data is subject to change without notice. Travelers are advised to contact individual businesses or organizations to obtain information to their satisfaction before traveling. Links to third-party websites are provided as a convenience to users; the Oregon Tourism Commission does not control or endorse the content or make any claims to the accuracy of the content.

### Google Analytics

User information from the Travel Oregon website is collected primarily to provide a more efficient experience. TravelOregon.com uses “cookies” “pixel tags” and “spotlight tags,” to provide more relevant content, advertising, and to improve the web site. These may be small text files which are put on your computer or small graphic files. Information provided through these methods is anonymous in nature. If you wish, you may set your browser to refuse cookies. Some cookies may remain on your computer until you manually delete them.

This web site uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses cookies to help the web site analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the web site (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the web site, compiling reports on web site activity for web site operators and providing other services relating to web site activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. Google offers opt-outs for analytics and for Google’s remarketing services.

Google’s use of your IP address and other data held by Google is governed by your preferences within Google’s product suite and Google’s privacy policies. Visit Google’s website for to view their privacy policies and opt-out options.  
In addition, this website may use third-party and partner advertiser cookies, pixel tags, or spotlight tags on select web pages. The purpose of these types of cookies, pixels, and tags is to collect and aggregate statistics about your visit to our website and/or to provide relevant re-marketing to you. These companies and partners may use information about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. These cookies do not contain personally identifiable information.

### Right to Complain

We work hard to handle your information responsibly. If you are unhappy about the way we do this, please lodge a complaint with [info@traveloregon.com](mailto:info@traveloregon.com).

We hope that we will be able to resolve any concerns you may have.

### Comment Policy

Travel Oregon encourages comments, critiques, questions, and suggestions. By posting comments on the Travel Oregon Network of sites you are agreeing to the following:

All comments left on the Travel Oregon network of sites are the responsibility of the commenter. By submitting a comment on our network of sites, you agree that the comment content is your own, and to hold this site, Travel Oregon, harmless from any and all repercussions, damages, or liability.

**Travel Oregon**  reserves the right to edit, delete, move, or mark as spam any and all comments and to block access by any individual or group from commenting or from the entire network of sites. The comment form must be filled in with a proper or legitimate sounding name and URL. Comments using keywords, spam or splog-like URLs or suspicious information in the comment form will be edited or deleted.

**Email Privacy:**  Valid email addresses are required for commenting, and they are not published, nor shared except as described above. They may be used by the site owner to privately contact the commenter.

**Commenter Privacy and Protection:**  All email, physical mail, phone numbers, and any private and personal information posted in any comment will be deleted as soon as possible to protect the privacy of the commenter. To prevent such editing, never share this private information within the comment.

**Language and Manners:**  This network of sites is “family friendly” and comments which include offensive or inappropriate language, or considered by the network of sites owner and administrator to be rude and offensive, will be edited or deleted.

  * We will not allow personal attacks or vulgar, abusive, offensive, threatening or harassing language. This includes creative spellings of swear words using asterisks or spaces between words.
  * We will not allow comments that contain sexual content or links to sexual content.
  * We will not allow comments that promote or advertise a person or a business or commercial transaction that is unrelated to travel within the state of Oregon.
  * We will not allow comments that promote or oppose any person campaigning for election to a political office or that promote or oppose any ballot measure.
  * We will not allow comments or posts that disclose information which the agency and its employees are required to keep confidential by law or administrative rule.

**Limit Links:**  This site is setup to automatically hold any comment with more than two links in moderation, which may delay your comment from appearing. Any comment with more than four links could be marked as comment spam.

**How Travel Oregon Will Respond:**  Comments will only be responded to in direct response to the comment. The site administrator(s) will not respond privately via email or other communication method to a comment.

**Comment Spam:**  Any comment assumed to be possible comment spam will be deleted and marked as comment spam.

**Commenters Blocked:**  Anyone who violates this Comments Policy may be blocked from future access and/or commenting on this network of sites.

**All Rights Reserved:**  The site owner, administrator, contributor, editor, and/or author reserve the right to edit, delete, move, or mark as spam any and all comments and to block access by any individual or group from commenting or from the entire network of sites.

**Trackbacks Are Comments:**  All trackbacks will be treated inline with our Comments Policy.
